<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.4j3aju"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0245858-200613084148143</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.4j3aju</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2021-04-08
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
{
  &quot;and&quot; : [
    &quot;Country is Brazil&quot;,
    &quot;OccurrenceStatus is Present&quot;,
    {
      &quot;or&quot; : [
        &quot;TaxonKey is Acanthella Hook.fil.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Aciotis D.Don&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Acisanthera P.Browne&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Dicrananthera C.Presl&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Dicrananthera K.B.Presl, 1832&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Noterophila Mart.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Rostranthera M.J.Rocha &amp; P.J.F.Guim.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Appendicularia DC.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Comolia DC.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Leiostegia Benth.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Ernestia DC.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Fritzschia Cham.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Macairea DC.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Marcetia DC.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Nepsera Naudin&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Pseudoernestia (Cogn.) Krasser&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Sandemania Gleason&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Siphanthera Pohl&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Siphanthera Pohl ex DC.&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Comoliopsis Wurdack&quot;,
        &quot;TaxonKey is Brasilianthus Almeda &amp; Michelang.&quot;
      ]
    }
  ]
}
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Herbarium (UNA)
1 records from MEXU/Tipos de plantas vasculares
1 records from Kathryn Kalmbach Herbarium
1 records from RSA - California Botanic Garden Herbarium
1 records from Herbario Amazónico Colombiano
1 records from HVAT - Herbário do Vale do Taquari
1 records from Museu Paraense Emilio Goeldi - Xiloteca Collection
1 records from Botany (UPS)
1 records from CEPEC herbarium - Centro de Pesquisas do Cacau - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
1 records from SPFw - Xiloteca do Instituto de Biociências da Universidade de São Paulo
1 records from DVPR - Herbário da Universidade Tecnológica Federal do Paraná - Dois Vizinhos
1 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
1 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
1 records from Plant Specimen Database of Tama Forest Science Garden, Forestry and Forest Products Research Institute, Japan
1 records from CONN
1 records from LUSC - Herbário de Lages da Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina
1 records from Museo Argentino de Ciencias Naturales &quot;Bernardino Rivadavia&quot; (MACN). Vascular Plants National Collection (BAv)
1 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
1 records from Taxon occurrence data for the FungalRoot database
1 records from Intermountain Herbarium (Vascular plants &amp; algae)
2 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL)
2 records from P herbarium - Muséum national d’histoire naturelle, Paris - Amostras Brasileiras Repatriadas - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
2 records from HUCPE - Herbário da Universidade Católica de Pernambuco
2 records from The Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Goettingen
2 records from Type herbarium, Göttingen (GOET)
2 records from MPUC - Herbário do Museu da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
2 records from IRAI - Herbário do Parque da Ciência Newton Freire Maia
2 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O) UiO
2 records from MOSS - Herbário Dárdano de Andrade Lima
2 records from HUEFS herbarium - Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana - Herbário Virtual REFLORA
3 records from Herbarium Berolinense, Berlin (B)
3 records from HAMAB - Herbário Amapaense
4 records from Colección de plantas vasculares de Brasil del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB-Brasil
4 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
4 records from Inventário florístico de 20 parcelas permanentes estabelecidas em áreas de savana do norte da Amazônia brasileira
4 records from Arizona State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
4 records from SMDB - Santa Maria Departamento de Biologia
4 records from HUSC - Herbário Unisanta
5 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
5 records from Herbário da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná - HUCP
5 records from HCDAL - Herbário Caririense Dárdano de Andrade-Lima
5 records from CRI - Herbário Pe. Dr. Raulino Reitz
5 records from DAV - UC Davis Herbarium
5 records from University of Vermont, Pringle Herbarium
5 records from iNaturalist Research-grade Observations
6 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB-CSIC-ICUB), BC-Plantae
6 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
6 records from HTSA - Herbário do Trópico Semiárido
6 records from University of Jena, Herbarium Haussknecht - Herbarium JE
6 records from Rapid Assessment Program (RAP) Biodiversity Survey Database
7 records from MPM Milwaukee Public Museum Herbarium
7 records from SLUI - Herbário Rosa Mochel
7 records from Herbarium specimens of Société des Sciences Naturelles et Mathématiques de Cherbourg (CHE)
8 records from HRCB - Herbário Rioclarense
8 records from JOI - Herbário Joinvillea
8 records from United Herbaria of the University and ETH Zurich
9 records from Herbarium Hamburgense
10 records from University of Florida Herbarium (FLAS)
11 records from HUESB - Herbário da Universidade Estadual do Sudoeste da Bahia
11 records from Carnegie Museum of Natural History Herbarium
11 records from FCAB - Herbário Friburguense
13 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
13 records from HVASF - Herbário Vale do São Francisco
13 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
13 records from Instituto de Botánica Darwinion
14 records from HUFSJ - Herbário da Universidade Federal de São João del-Rei
14 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
15 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
17 records from TEPB - Herbário Graziela Barroso
17 records from FURB - Herbário Dr. Roberto Miguel Klein
17 records from EFC - Herbário Escola de Florestas Curitiba
18 records from HPL - Herbário do Jardim Botânico Plantarum
19 records from HUTO - Herbário da Universidade de Tocantins
19 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
21 records from HUEG - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Goiás
21 records from PACA-AGP - Herbarium Anchieta
21 records from HFSL - Herbário Dr. Ary Tupinambá Penna Pinheiro
21 records from HJ - Herbario Jataiense
21 records from EAFM - Herbário do Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia do Amazonas
22 records from R-Tipos - Herbário do Museu Nacional - Tipos
23 records from HDJF - Herbário Dendrológico Jeanine Felfili
23 records from Herbario Nacional Colombiano (COL)
23 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
25 records from HAS - Herbário Alarich Rudolf Holger Schultz
25 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany) - Historical Photographs of Type Specimens from Berlin (B)
26 records from MAR - Herbário do Maranhão
26 records from UESC - Herbário Universidade Estadual de Santa Cruz
26 records from HBRA - Herbário do Instituto de Estudos Costeiros da Universidade Federal do Pará
28 records from UFMT - Herbário UFMT
28 records from ICN - Herbário do Instituto de Ciências Naturais
30 records from Funed-Pol - Coleção de lâminas de grãos de pólen
31 records from MFS - Herbário Profª. Drª. Marlene Freitas da Silva
34 records from CVRD - Herbário da Reserva Natural Vale
34 records from CPAP - Herbário CPAP
34 records from HERBAM - Herbário da Amazônia Meridional
36 records from BOTU - Herbário Irina Delanova Gemtchújnicov
37 records from CNMT - Herbário Centro Norte Mato Grossense
43 records from HUEM - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Maringá
49 records from HURB - Herbário do Recôncavo da Bahia
50 records from BHZB - Herbário do Jardim Botânico da Fundação Zoo-Botânica de Belo Horizonte
52 records from PEUFR - Herbário Professor Vasconcelos Sobrinho
54 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
54 records from R - Herbário do Museu Nacional
56 records from SORO - Herbário do Centro de Ciências e Tecnologias para a Sustentabilidade
56 records from IAC - Herbário do Instituto Agronômico de Campinas
58 records from EAC - Herbário Prisco Bezerra
59 records from HCF - Herbário da Universidade Tecnológica Federal do Paraná Campus Campo Mourão
59 records from SJRP - Herbário de São José do Rio Preto
65 records from FUEL - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Londrina
67 records from UFG - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Goiás
68 records from HST - Herbário Sérgio Tavares
74 records from SPSF - Herbário Dom Bento José Pickel
75 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
76 records from UFP - Herbário UFP - Geraldo Mariz
77 records from VIES - Herbário Central da Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo
86 records from VIC - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Viçosa
89 records from MBML-Herbario - Herbário Mello Leitão
92 records from Caatinga Biome - RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
99 records from HEPH - Herbário Ezechias Paulo Heringer
122 records from ASE - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Sergipe
125 records from CESJ - Herbário Leopoldo Krieger
126 records from JPB - Herbário Lauro Pires Xavier
128 records from FLOR - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica da Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina
129 records from MAC - Herbário do Instituto do Meio Ambiente do Estado de Alagoas
131 records from Geneva Herbarium – De Candolle&apos;s Prodromus (G-DC)
138 records from OUPR - Herbário &quot;Professor José Badini&quot;
139 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
178 records from CGMS - Herbário da Fundação Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul
185 records from IPA - Herbário - IPA Dárdano de Andrade Lima
195 records from CEN - Herbário da Embrapa Recursos Genéticos e Biotecnologia
260 records from ESA - Herbário da Escola Superior de Agricultura Luiz de Queiroz
306 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
332 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
334 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
364 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
459 records from UB - Herbário da Universidade de Brasília
492 records from UPCB - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica
555 records from ALCB - Herbário Alexandre Leal Costa
557 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
592 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
641 records from CEPEC - Herbário do Centro de Pesquisas do Cacau
650 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
664 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
713 records from Museu Paraense Emilio Goeldi Herbarium
739 records from SPF - Herbário da Universidade de São Paulo
769 records from BHCB - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais
824 records from Herbarium - Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas da Amazônia (INPA)
845 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
1111 records from HUEFS - Herbario da Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana
1138 records from HUFU - Herbarium Uberlandense
1165 records from UEC - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Campinas
1207 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
1556 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records
1802 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
2121 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2021-04-08T20:38:29Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.4j3aju">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.4j3aju</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">https://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0245858-200613084148143.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
