<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="bf2a4bf0-5f31-11de-b67e-b8a03c50a862"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
      <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/ypoair</alternateIdentifier>
        <alternateIdentifier>8402</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>Rob Cubey</surName>
    </individualName>
    </creator>
      <pubDate>
      2018-11-18
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>RBGE&amp;#39;s extensive Herbarium numbers nearly three million specimens representing half to two thirds of the world&amp;#39;s flora.
        It is considered a leading botanical collection, and every year many researchers from around the world visit to study our specimens in a well-designed and user-friendly
        setting.
        Edinburgh incorporates the following herbaria :- 
        CTN: Herbarium, Free Library and Museum, Campbeltown, Strathclyde Region, Scotland U.K.
        EBH: Herbarium, Botanical Society of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Scotland U.K.
        EDH: Herbarium, Plinian Society, Edinburgh, Scotland U.K.
        EGH: Herbarium, University of Edinburgh, Edinburgh, Scotland U.K.
        GL: (except British) on permanent loan: Herbarium, Botany Department, University of Glasgow, Glasgow G12 8QQ, Scotland U.K.
        KSO: Herbarium, Tweedside Physical and Antiquarian Society Museum
        Kelso, Borders Region, Scotland U.K.
        NCCE: Herbarium, Nature Conservancy Council, 12 Hope Terrace, Edinburgh, Scotland U.K.
        NCE: (tropical pteridophytes): Herbarium, School of Biological Sciences, University of Newcastle upon Tyne, Newcastle upon Tyne NE1 7RU, England U.K.</para>
    </abstract>
        <keywordSet>
              <keyword>Herbarium Plant Specimens R.K. Greville J.H. Balfour Peter Davis George Walker Arnott</keyword>
        </keywordSet>
      <intellectualRights>
        <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial (CC-BY-NC) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
      </intellectualRights>
      <distribution scope="document">
          <online>
              <url function="information">http://www.rbge.org.uk/science/herbarium</url>
          </online>
      </distribution>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2021-01-15T00:47:05Z</dateStamp>
      <citation>Rob Cubey (2018). Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E). Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh. Occurrence dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/ypoair accessed via GBIF.org on 2021-01-15.</citation>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
