<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.1/eml.xsd"
        packageId="10.15468/dl.iv2muw"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
  xml:lang="en">

<dataset>
        <alternateIdentifier>0012888-190415153152247</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.iv2muw</title>
    <creator>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </creator>
    <metadataProvider>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>    </metadataProvider>
      <pubDate>
      2019-05-14
      </pubDate>
    <language>ENGLISH</language>
    <abstract>
        <para>A dataset containing all occurrences available in GBIF matching the query:
Country: Brazil 
TaxonKey: Mimosa L.
The dataset includes records from the following constituent datasets. The full metadata for each constituent is also included in this archive:
1 records from Aranzadi Zientzi Elkartea
1 records from Auckland Museum Botany Collection
1 records from herbario
1 records from DAV UC Davis Center for Plant Diversity
1 records from United States National Plant Germplasm System Collection
1 records from PlantBank Records
1 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO-Briof
1 records from Lund Botanical Museum (LD)
1 records from University of Florida Herbarium (FLAS)
1 records from University of Michigan Herbarium
1 records from Sammlung Ernst Ule sinenumero Herbarium Hamburgense HBG
1 records from Xiloteca del IANIGLA (IANIGLA-CCT CONICET Mendoza): XIAM.
1 records from UTEP Plants (Arctos)
1 records from University of North Carolina Chapel Hill Herbarium
1 records from Herbario Gaspar Xuarez (BAA) - Facultad de Agronomía - Universidad de Buenos Aires
1 records from Bolivian Mimosa (Leguminosae, Mimosoideae): three new species and a species checklist
1 records from Manchester Museum, University of Manchester, Botany Collection
1 records from UCBG TAPIR Provider
1 records from Estonian University of Life Sciences
1 records from Fungus Collections at Staatliches Museum für Naturkunde Karlsruhe (Herbarium KR)
2 records from The AAU Herbarium Database
2 records from VIT Herbarium - Vascular Plants (The Natural History Museum of Alava)
3 records from MGC Herbarium of University of Malaga (Spain): MGC-Cormof dataset
3 records from SINGER Coordinator
3 records from Geographically tagged INSDC sequences
3 records from University of British Columbia Herbarium (UBC) - Vascular Plant Collection
3 records from Modelación de la distribución real y potencial de especies de dos géneros de Mimosoideae: Mimosa y Prosopis (Leguminosae) en México
3 records from Computarización de la xiloteca Dr. Faustino Miranda del Instituto de Ecología, AC
4 records from Universidad de Oviedo. Departamento de Biología de Organismos y Sistemas: FCO
4 records from Actualización de las bases de datos del Herbario XAL. Fase III
4 records from Inventário florístico de 20 parcelas permanentes estabelecidas em áreas de savana do norte da Amazônia brasileira
4 records from JOIw - Xiloteca Joinvillea
4 records from North Carolina State University Vascular Plant Herbarium
5 records from Colección de plantas vasculares del herbario de la Universitat de València (VAL).
5 records from Institut Botanic de Barcelona (IBB-CSIC-ICUB), BC-Plantae
5 records from Bernice P. Bishop Museum
5 records from CAS Botany (BOT)
5 records from Herbarium specimens of Société des Sciences Naturelles et Mathématiques de Cherbourg (CHE)
5 records from naturgucker
6 records from Herbario de la Universidad de Sevilla
6 records from Herbario CTES Plantas Vasculares
6 records from Botany (UPS)
6 records from Dados da ocorrência de plantas lenhosas em um gradiente de perturbação/precipitação em área de Caatinga, Parque Nacional do Catimbau, Buíque, PE, Brasil
6 records from University of Vienna, Institute for Botany - Herbarium WU
6 records from BOTUw - Xiloteca &quot;Profa. Dra. Maria Aparecida Mourão Brasil&quot;
6 records from SANT Herbarium vascular plants collection
7 records from Herbario de Plantas Vasculares de la Universidad de Salamanca: SALA
7 records from MEXU/Tipos de plantas vasculares
7 records from Rapid Assessment Program (RAP) Biodiversity Survey Database
7 records from Catálogo electrónico de especímenes depositados en el Herbario de la Universidad de Texas en Austin, Fase IV
7 records from Herbaria of the University and ETH Zürich
8 records from HTSA-Carpoteca - Carpoteca do Trópico Semiárido
8 records from HTSAw - Xiloteca do Trópico Semiárido
8 records from (Fig. 4) Pollen analysis of the Campo Salgado core
9 records from Herbarium of Vascular Plants Collection of the University of Extremadura (Spain)
9 records from Herbarium Senckenbergianum (FR)
9 records from iNaturalist Research-grade Observations
9 records from HUSC - Herbário Unisanta
10 records from Herbarium Berolinense
10 records from SysTax - Herbaria
10 records from Bioversity Collecting Mission Database
11 records from HBRA - Herbário do Instituto de Estudos Costeiros da Universidade Federal do Pará
13 records from Herbarium (UNA)
13 records from UFACPZ - Herbário da Universidade Federal do Acre
13 records from Herbaria of the University and ETH Zürich
14 records from The System-wide Information Network for Genetic Resources (SINGER)
14 records from HUCPE - Herbário da Universidade Católica de Pernambuco
15 records from HFSL - Herbário Dr. Ary Tupinambá Penna Pinheiro
17 records from Herbarium Erlangense
17 records from (Fig. 5) Pollen analysis of the Furo do Chato core
19 records from HPAN - Herbário do Pantanal &quot;Vali Joana Pott&quot;
20 records from FCAB - Herbário Friburguense
22 records from (Fig. 3) Pollen analysis of the Bosque de Avicennia core
22 records from EAFM - Herbário do Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia do Amazonas
23 records from UFG - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Goiás
24 records from UFMT - Herbário UFMT
25 records from HERBAM - Herbário da Amazônia Meridional
25 records from HPBR - Herbário Padre Balduino Rambo
26 records from University of South Florida Herbarium (USF)
26 records from Natural History Museum (London) Collection Specimens
27 records from EURISCO, The European Genetic Resources Search Catalogue
29 records from CNMT - Herbário Centro Norte Mato Grossense
29 records from SPFw - Xiloteca do Instituto de Biociências da Universidade de São Paulo
30 records from Herbarium specimens of Université de Montpellier 2, Institut de Botanique (MPU))
34 records from Moscow University Herbarium (MW)
35 records from HDJF - Herbário Dendrológico Jeanine Felfili
35 records from DVPR - Herbário da Universidade Tecnológica Federal do Paraná - Dois Vizinhos
36 records from HVAT - Herbário do Vale do Taquari
37 records from HAMAB - Herbário Amapaense
42 records from HUFSJ - Herbário da Universidade Federal de São João del-Rei
43 records from CVRD - Herbário da Reserva Natural Vale
43 records from SMDB - Santa Maria Departamento de Biologia
45 records from IRAI - Herbário do Parque da Ciência Newton Freire Maia
46 records from Herbarium Hamburgense
49 records from CRI - Herbário Pe. Dr. Raulino Reitz
51 records from SLUI - Herbário Rosa Mochel
51 records from Funed-Pol - Coleção de lâminas de grãos de pólen
53 records from Vascular Plant Herbarium, Oslo (O)
54 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Herbarium Tubingense
55 records from MFS - Herbário Profª. Drª. Marlene Freitas da Silva
56 records from HUCO - Herbário da Universidade Estadual do Centro-Oeste
57 records from SORO - Herbário do Centro de Ciências e Tecnologias para a Sustentabilidade
59 records from Colección de plantas vasculares de Brasil del Herbario &quot;Jaime Andrés Rodríguez&quot;. LEB-Brasil
64 records from JOI - Herbário Joinvillea
66 records from Occurrences in SinBIOTA
66 records from BHZB - Herbário do Jardim Botânico da Fundação Zoo-Botânica de Belo Horizonte
70 records from MBML-Herbario - Herbário Mello Leitão
74 records from LUSC - Herbário de Lages da Universidade do Estado de Santa Catarina
76 records from HPL - Herbário do Jardim Botânico Plantarum
77 records from HUTO - Herbário da Universidade de Tocantins
77 records from SJRP - Herbário de São José do Rio Preto
84 records from Royal Botanic Garden Edinburgh Herbarium (E)
91 records from HRCB - Herbário Rioclarense
92 records from HUEG - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Goiás
93 records from HUESB - Herbário da Universidade Estadual do Sudoeste da Bahia
95 records from Harvard University Herbaria: All Records
95 records from HJ - Herbario Jataiense Prof. Germano Guarim Neto
108 records from MPUC - Herbário do Museu da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Rio Grande do Sul
118 records from MAR - Herbário do Maranhão
118 records from Meise Botanic Garden Herbarium (BR)
123 records from OUPR - Herbário &quot;Professor José Badini&quot;
125 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany) - Historical Photographs of Type Specimens from Berlin (B)
127 records from HTSA - Herbário do Trópico Semiárido
128 records from Museo Argentino de Ciencias Naturales &quot;Bernardino Rivadavia&quot; (MACN). Actuopalynology National Collection (BAPa)
128 records from Geneva Herbarium – General Collection (G)
133 records from MEL AVH data
134 records from UESC - Herbário Universidade Estadual de Santa Cruz
144 records from HUEM - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Maringá
153 records from CSIC-Real Jardín Botánico-Colección de Plantas Vasculares (MA)
160 records from HURB - Herbário do Recôncavo da Bahia
163 records from Herbário da Pontifícia Universidade Católica do Paraná - HUCP
168 records from HCDAL - Herbário Caririense Dárdano de Andrade-Lima
183 records from R-Tipos - Herbário do Museu Nacional - Tipos
185 records from EFC - Herbário Escola de Florestas Curitiba
203 records from The Vascular Plant Collection at the Botanische Staatssammlung München
210 records from EAN - Herbário Jaime Coelho de Moraes
232 records from HAS - Herbário Alarich Rudolf Holger Schultz
243 records from MAC - Herbário do Instituto do Meio Ambiente do Estado de Alagoas
245 records from IAC - Herbário do Instituto Agronômico de Campinas
260 records from CPAP - Herbário CPAP
262 records from UFP - Herbário UFP - Geraldo Mariz
266 records from BOTU - Herbário Irina Delanova Gemtchújnicov
268 records from FURB - Herbário Dr. Roberto Miguel Klein
283 records from HST - Herbário Sérgio Tavares
294 records from HCF - Herbário da Universidade Tecnológica Federal do Paraná Campus Campo Mourão
306 records from MOSS - Herbário Dárdano de Andrade Lima
319 records from HUCS - Herbário da Universidade de Caxias do Sul
328 records from ASE - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Sergipe
329 records from SPSF - Herbário Dom Bento José Pickel
348 records from HEPH - Herbário Ezechias Paulo Heringer
374 records from TEPB - Herbário Graziela Barroso
374 records from Phanerogamic Botanical Collections (S)
379 records from CESJ - Herbário Leopoldo Krieger
391 records from FUEL - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Londrina
393 records from UPCB - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica
397 records from HVASF - Herbário Vale do São Francisco
408 records from PEUFR - Herbário Professor Vasconcelos Sobrinho
423 records from HUFU - Herbarium Uberlandense
426 records from VIES - Herbário Central da Universidade Federal do Espírito Santo
427 records from JPB - Herbário Lauro Pires Xavier
454 records from FLOR - Herbário do Departamento de Botânica da Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina
469 records from Natural History Museum, Vienna - Herbarium W
479 records from Instituto de Botánica Darwinion
538 records from The vascular plants collection (P) at the Herbarium of the Muséum national d&apos;Histoire Naturelle (MNHN - Paris)
573 records from Museu Paraense Emilio Goeldi Herbarium
589 records from Naturalis Biodiversity Center (NL) - Botany
603 records from VIC - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Viçosa
617 records from PACA-AGP - Herbarium Anchieta
742 records from Herbarium - Instituto Nacional de Pesquisas da Amazônia (INPA)
797 records from BHCB - Herbário da Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais
861 records from ALCB - Herbário Alexandre Leal Costa
893 records from CGMS - Herbário da Fundação Universidade Federal de Mato Grosso do Sul
1003 records from R - Herbário do Museu Nacional
1125 records from EAC - Herbário Prisco Bezerra
1200 records from ESA - Herbário da Escola Superior de Agricultura Luiz de Queiroz
1227 records from CEPEC - Herbário do Centro de Pesquisas do Cacau
1280 records from SP - Herbário do Estado &quot;Maria Eneyda P. Kaufmann Fidalgo&quot; - Coleção de Fanerógamas
1291 records from IPA - Herbário - IPA Dárdano de Andrade Lima
1295 records from ICN - Herbário do Instituto de Ciências Naturais
1340 records from Field Museum of Natural History (Botany)  Seed Plant Collection
1376 records from Tropicos Specimen Data
1532 records from UEC - Herbário da Universidade Estadual de Campinas
1611 records from CEN - Herbário da Embrapa Recursos Genéticos e Biotecnologia
1997 records from SPF - Herbário da Universidade de São Paulo
2368 records from NMNH Extant Specimen Records
2988 records from UB - Herbário da Universidade de Brasília
3011 records from Royal Botanic Gardens, Kew - Herbarium Specimens
3362 records from MBM - Herbário do Museu Botânico Municipal
3462 records from HUEFS - Herbario da Universidade Estadual de Feira de Santana
5042 records from The New York Botanical Garden Herbarium (NY)
5164 records from RB - Rio de Janeiro Botanical Garden Herbarium Collection
</para>
    </abstract>
      <contact>
    <individualName>
          <surName>GBIF Download Service</surName>
    </individualName>
<electronicMailAddress>support@gbif.org</electronicMailAddress>      </contact>

</dataset>

<additionalMetadata>
    <metadata>
      <gbif>
        <dateStamp>2019-05-14T16:50:24Z</dateStamp>
      <citation identifier="10.15468/dl.iv2muw">GBIF Occurrence Download 10.15468/dl.iv2muw</citation>
              <physical>
                  <objectName>Darwin Core Archive</objectName>
                  <characterEncoding>UTF-8</characterEncoding>
                  <dataFormat>
                      <externallyDefinedFormat>
                          <formatName>Darwin Core Archive</formatName>
                      </externallyDefinedFormat>
                  </dataFormat>
                  <distribution>
                      <online>
                          <url function="download">http://api.gbif.org/v1/occurrence/download/request/0012888-190415153152247.zip</url>
                      </online>
                  </distribution>
              </physical>
        </gbif>
    </metadata>
</additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
